ZACK POLLARD

1 The Pyghtle, Westoning, MK45 5LJ github.com/zackpollard \diamond git.zackpollard.pro

Mobile: 07928015705 \diamond Email: z.r.e.pollard-14@student.lboro.ac.uk

PROFILE

A Loughborough University graduate with a 1st class BSc in Computer Science. Systems Administrator and Programmer with 9 years of experience, through both freelance work and employment. Primarily works using Java with varied experience in other languages including C++, Python and Node.JS.

EDUCATION

Loughborough University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (1st Class)

Dissertation: Secure Smart Lock System

Harlington Upper School

GCSE and Sixth Form

· A Levels: Mathematics (A), Physics (B), ICT (C)

· Level 3 BTECs: Subsidiary Diploma in Sport (Distinction*)

- 11 GCSEs: Grades A* C in Mathematics, Advanced Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Business and Communication Systems, English Language, English Literature, Music, D&T Product Design and Religious Studies
- · Level 2 BTECs: OCR National First Certificate in ICT (Distinction) and Extended Certificate in Sport (Distinction*)

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM - iX Studios London

 $Interactive\ Developer$

July 2016 - July 2017

September 2014 - July 2018

Loughborough, Leicestershire

September 2009 - July 2014

Harlington, Bedfordshire

Southbank, London

- · Working directly with clients from Deutsche Bank and BP.
- · Built a custom development pipeline using Jenkins 2.0 for the Deutsche Bank development team paving the way to increased productivity and automation.
- · Onboarded a new team onto the Deutsche Bank project whilst operating as the technical lead on-site for IBM.
- · Worked within an agile team, both local and remote to produce a high quality Android application
- · Designed and implemented a custom solution for making a single android application for multiple different markets globally

Woodlands Middle School

Assistant Systems and Network Technician

July 2011 and July 2012 Flitwick, Bedfordshire

- · Provided technical support to users in a clear and concise manner.
- · Kept to a schedule and completed jobs within required deadlines.
- \cdot Problem solving under pressure in time-sensitive situations.
- · Worked effectively with members of a team to coordinate network repair tasks in order to prevent interference with users on the network.

Freelancing 2009 - Present

Java Development and Systems Administration

- · Dealing with clients requirements on a daily basis.
- · Managing time and providing accurate time frames for completion of projects.
- · Working as part of a team on projects utilising git for version control.
- · Persevering with problems to find acceptable solutions.

Flitwick Cricket Club

April 2014 - January 2017

Flitwick, Bedfordshire

Bartender - Part Time

- · Dealing with customers and carrying out their requests accurately.
- · Working as part of a team, communicating with each other in order to keep everything running smoothly.
- · Keeping calm in high-pressure situations such as large events.

KEY SKILLS AND BEHAVIOURS

- **Problem Solving:** Evident through freelance work that required an unconventional approach to solving problems introduced by client requirements.
- · Communication: This has been essential throughout all work in order to communicate with both clients and employers.
- **Time Management:** An essential skill demonstrated consistently during freelance and university work, both of which have a set time frame for completion.
- **Teamwork:** Demonstrated throughout many freelance projects and essential to ensure completion of tasks efficiently and before deadlines.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Languages Java, C++, Python, Lua, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, AJAX, Node.JS,

Groovy

Data Structures XML, JSON, YAML

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools Git, Vim, Bash, Maven, Jenkins, LaTeX, KVM, SSH, VNC, JIRA, Docker,

Google Cloud, IBM Bluemix, RxJava, Retrofit

Operating Systems CentOS 6/7 (Redhat), Debian, Arch (Arch), UnRAID, Cisco IOS, MacOS,

Windows

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

SaxophoneABRSM Grade 8PianoABRSM Grade 6Music TheoryABRSM Grade 5

Kayaking & Canoeing Canoe England BCU 2 Star

Full UK Clean Driving Licence

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- · Played the Saxophone and Piano for 13 and 15 years respectively.
- · Participated in various bands throughout Middle and Upper School, as well as playing in the University Jazz band, Tuxedo Swing.
- · Kayaking, Canoeing, Mountain Biking and Rock Climbing for 8 years.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.